Please read Luke 11:5-13
请阅读路加福音 11:5-13
There are bits and pieces of verses from the Bible which sound like prayer is all about getting what you want.
圣经中有一些经文片段，听起来像是祷告就是为了得到你想要的。
Some of them come from this passage.
其中一些来自这段经文。
Whether it's prayer for a loved one to be saved, or prayer for your own salvation
无论是为所爱的人得救祷告，还是为自己的得救祷告
prayer for healing, prayer for wealth, popularity, and success of any sort
祈求治愈、祈求财富、声望和任何形式的成功
or prayer for protection in dangerous situations
或祷告在危险情况下得到保护
we do seem to have a strong belief that God is just there waiting for us to ask for something
我们似乎坚信上帝就在那里等着我们祈求什么
so that he can give it.
这样他就可以给了。
But something is wrong with this approach, and it bothers me.
但是这种方法有问题，这让我很困扰。
I keep saying that people get into trouble spiritually
我一直说人们在属灵上会遇到麻烦
because they take half a truth and run with it. It happens all the time, unfortunately.
因为他们接受了一半的真理并实践之。不幸的是，这样的事情总是发生。
In general, they want to claim all the promises--all the fun stuff--
总的来说，他们想要得到所有的承诺——所有有趣的东西——
and then skip all the commands, and all the more unpleasant stuff.
然后跳过所有命令，以及所有更不愉快的东西。
Really, it should be just the other way around.
真相是，它应该是相反的。
The promises are God's business, and the commands are our responsibility...whether we like it or not.
应许是上帝的事，命令是我们的责任……无论我们喜欢与否。
This same problem is at its worst when it comes to salvation.
当涉及到救恩时，同样的问题是最糟糕的。
You wouldn't believe how many people write to me and straight-out say, "no way!"
你很难相信有多少人给我写信并直截了当地说，“不可能！”
"I'm not going to obey Jesus; at least not now.
“我不会顺服耶稣；至少现在不会。
"Maybe someday, but I'm not ready for it yet. It would make me unpopular or lead to tension with my family.
“也许有一天，但我还没有准备好。这会让我不受欢迎或导致与家人关系紧张。
"I would freeze or starve to death." And on and on with one excuse after another.
“我会冻死或饿死。”一个又一个的借口。
But then they finish off with talk about how they're just going to keep serving God
但是他们最后谈论他们将如何继续事奉上帝
by sharing the faith wherever they can.
通过尽可能的分享信仰。
And then they thank God profusely in my presence for loving them so much
然后他们在我面前非常感谢上帝如此爱他们
and for having saved them, like there's no connection at all between their arrogance
也因为救了他们，就像他们的傲慢与
about what Jesus has told us to do, and their assumption that God is still going to save them.
耶稣告诉我们要做的事情没有任何的关系，以及他们认为上帝仍会拯救他们。
They talk about what a wonderful God he is, because he's going to save them no matter what.
他们谈论他是多么美妙的上帝，因为无论如何他都会拯救他们。
So what have they done?
那么他们做了什么？
They have done the same as all the Voodoo worshipers and witch doctors in the world.
他们和世界上所有的巫毒崇拜者和巫医一样。
They have assumed that if they pick and choose the right bits and pieces of the Bible
他们假设如果他们挑选正确的圣经片段
they can devise a formula where they can control God
他们可以设计一个公式来控制上帝
and they can have it all their way without ever having to obey Jesus even once.
他们可以一路走好，甚至一次都不必顺服耶稣。
Before we go back to that passage of scripture from Jesus in Luke 11, I want to explain something.
在我们回到路加福音 11 章耶稣的那段经文之前，我想解释一些事情。
The Gospels were written for people who had already accepted Jesus and all that he taught.
福音书是为已经接受耶稣和他所教导的一切的人写的。
For some of them, they had started following Jesus many years earlier.
他们中的一些人多年前就开始跟随耶稣。
The Gospels were written for these people in the early church
福音书是为早期教会中的这些人而写的
about thirty five years after Jesus ascended to heaven.
耶稣升天后大约三十五年。
They were written so they would not forget the most important things that he said.
是为了他们不会忘记他所说的最重要的事情而写的。
So there were times when the writers just naturally assumed
所以有时候作者们会很自然地假设
that people reading the Gospels would have the overall picture.
读福音书的人会有整体的画面。
They weren't operating on the assumption that every single verse had to be complete in and of itself.
他们并没有假设每一节经文本身都必须是完整的。
Every piece was part of a bigger picture which had grown out of them just naturally obeying Jesus
每一块都是一幅更大图景的一部分，这幅图景是由他们自然地顺服耶稣而形成的
for all those years.
在他们顺服的那些年。
You can see it right there in the context of this eleventh chapter of Luke.
你可以在路加福音第十一章的上下文中看到它。
Jesus is addressing men who have given up everything to follow him
耶稣正在对那些放弃一切跟随他的人说话
and they are wanting to get a clearer understanding about exactly what prayer is supposed to achieve
他们想要更清楚地了解祷告应该达到什么目的
and how it works.
以及它是如何工作的。
So Jesus says, "it's all about sorting out just how serious you are about what you want.
所以耶稣说，“这一切都是为了弄清楚你对自己想要的东西有多认真。
"How serious are you about following me?
“你有多么认真的跟着我？
"How serious are you about building the kingdom of heaven that I've been talking about?
“你对我说的建立天国是真的相信的吗？
"How serious are you about laying down your life for me?"
“你有多真诚的要为我舍命？”
You see, it's not about being cured of cancer, or getting a good job, or finding a nice girlfriend
你看，这不是治愈癌症，或者找到一份好工作，或者找到一个好女朋友
or even about your husband, or your children, or the people next door being saved.
甚至不是关于你的丈夫、你的孩子，或者隔壁的人得救。
Now, you may think it's unfair of me to say that
现在，你可能认为我这样说是不公平的
and you will find support for your position in some of what is written here.
您会在此处所写的一些内容中找到对您立场的支持。
It sounds like you can just name it and claim it.
听起来你可以给它命名并声明它。
In a way, that does work.
在某种程度上，这确实有效。
If the only thing in the world that you want is a million dollar house
如果在这世界上你只想要一百万美元的房子
and you are ready to sacrifice everything else on earth to get it; there is a very good chance that you will get it.
你准备牺牲地球上的一切来得到它；你很有可能得到它。
And then you can say, "see? it worked for me. It'll work for you.
然后你可以说，“看到了吗？这对我有用。这也会对你有用。
"It's right there in the Bible. God's plan for unlimited prosperity. It goes like this:
“它就在圣经里。上帝对无限繁荣的计划。它是这样的：
"Though God will not give it to you because you are a follower of him
“虽然上帝不会因为你是他的追随者就给你
"if you pester him long enough, he'll give it to you just to get you off his back.
“如果你纠缠他的时间够长，他会把它给你，只是为了摆脱你。
"There it is. Right there, in verse 8.
“就在那里。就在那里，在第 8 节。
"Jesus himself taught it. Can you see it?
“耶稣自己教的。你能看到吗？
"You name it, you claim it. And you keep on claiming it long enough, and you'll get it
“你命名它，你宣告它。你继续宣告它足够长的时间，你就会得到它
"whether God wants you to have it or not.
“无论上帝希望你拥有与否。
"You can control God. Praise the Lord! Hallelujah!"
“你可以控制上帝。赞美主！哈利路亚！”
Verses 9 and 10 support it even more: "Ask and it shall be given you, seek and you shall find
第 9 节和第 10 节更加支持它：“祈求就给你，寻找就寻见
"knock and it shall be opened unto you.
“扣门，就给你开门。
"For every one that asks receives, and he that seeks finds, and to him that knocks it shall be opened."
“凡祈求的，就得着，寻找的，就寻见，叩门的，就给他开门。”
Praise God! We have unlocked the code. This is your key to God's bank.
赞美神！我们已经解锁了密码。这是你进入上帝银行的钥匙。
You have him in a stranglehold and he has no choice but to give you what you ask for.
你把他束缚住了，他别无选择，只能满足你的要求。
But then...
但是之后...
Jesus gives the bigger picture.
耶稣给出了大一些的图景。
And like I keep saying, the problem in understanding the teachings of Jesus
就像我一直说的，理解耶稣教义的问题
always comes because people run off with a half truth.
因为人们总是只带着一半的真相。
The truth is usually not that hard to see if we really want to see it.
如果我们真的想看到它，真相通常并不难看。
But we have to be open to hearing what we don't naturally want to hear.
但是我们必须对听到我们本性不想听到的东西持开放态度。
In this case, it comes in two stages.
在这种情况下，它分为两个阶段。
The truth in the first stage shifts the emphasis slightly, but it is not immediately obvious.
第一阶段的真相稍微转移了重点，但并不是立即显而易见。
"If a son shall ask bread of any of you that is a father, will he give him a stone?
“如果有儿子向你们中的任何一个父亲要饼，他会给他石头吗？
"Or if he ask a fish, will he for a fish give him a serpent?
“或者如果他求一条鱼，他会给他一条蛇吗？
"Or if he shall ask an egg, will he offer him a scorpion?"
“或者如果他要一个鸡蛋，他会给他一只蝎子吗？”
This much is still talking about the father giving us what we're asking for, right?
这仍然是在谈论父亲给了我们我们所要求的东西，对吧？
But do you notice that Jesus has brought another factor into the story here? Can you see it?
但是你有没有注意到耶稣在这个故事中加入了另一个因素？你能看见它吗？
Come on, it's there if you look.
来吧，如果你看，它就在那里。
He has compared something that is good for you with something that is bad for you. Can you see it now?
他将一些对你有益的事物与对你不利的事物进行了比较。你现在能看到吗？
And this is the part which the "name it and claim it" prosperity teachers consistently overlook.
而这正是“命名并宣告”成功教师一贯忽视的部分。
Some will try to convince you that your selfish desires are good for you.
有些人会试图说服你，你的自私欲望对你有好处。
After all, you'll be able to do so much more for God if only you were rich
毕竟，只要你富有，你就能为上帝做更多的事
if only you are in complete health, if only you are famous and popular.
只要你身体健康，只要你出名和受欢迎。
But have a look at what the epistles say about this.
但是看看新约书信是怎么说的。
Paul writes to Timothy and he says, "they that would be rich have pierced themselves through many sorrows."
保罗写信给提摩太，他说：“那些贪恋钱财的人，已经被许多愁苦刺透了。”
He goes on to say, "the love of money is"...what?
他接着说，“对金钱的爱是”……什么？
What is the love of money? It's the root of all evil.
什么是爱钱？是万恶之源。
And what is it that the prosperity teachers are telling you to ask for? "Money", people shout. "Money".
成功导师告诉你要祈求什么？ “钱”，人们喊道。 “钱”。
"Not the love of money. The love of money is evil. But money itself...well, the more you can get, the better."
“不是爱钱。爱钱是邪恶的。但钱本身……好吧，你得到的越多越好。”
Seriously, does that sound like somebody who despises money or does it sound like someone who loves money?
说真的，这听起来像一个鄙视金钱的人还是听起来像一个爱钱的人？
Jesus said that if you try to work for God and work for money (or Mammon) at the same time
耶稣说，如果你同时为上帝工作和为金钱（或玛门）工作
you're going to end up despising one and loving the other.
你最终会鄙视一个而爱另一个。
Which one do you despise?
你鄙视哪一个？
Now, listen to what James says in his epistle:
现在，请听雅各在他的书信中说：
He says, "you ask and you do not receive because you ask amiss, that you may consume it upon your lusts."
他说：“你们求也得不着，因为你们妄求，叫你们随欲消费。”
Does that sound like what the prosperity gospel teachers preach?
这听起来像成功福音教师所宣扬的吗？
Of course not. They hate James almost as much as they hate Jesus.
当然不是。他们讨厌雅各几乎和他们讨厌耶稣一样。
So here we have, from James, a promise of a different color.
所以在这里，我们从詹姆斯那里得到了一种不同颜色的承诺。
He implies pretty strongly that you will not get what you ask for if you ask amiss, as he puts it.
他非常强烈地暗示，如果你问错了，你不会得到你想要的，正如他所说的。
That means you're asking for the wrong thing.
这意味着你要求错误的东西。
It's not expressed so clearly in the passage we are now reading from Luke 11
在我们现在读到的路加福音 11 章的经文中，它没有表达得如此清楚
but Jesus does say that a loving father will not give you something that is bad for you.
但耶稣确实说过，慈爱的父亲不会给你一些对你不利的东西。
If you pray for a fish, which was a symbol for Jesus in Bible times,
如果你祈求一条鱼，那是圣经时代耶稣的象征，
then yes, for sure, he'll give that to you.
那么是的，当然，他会给你的。
But if you pray for a snake, which is a symbol for the devil, he won't give that to you, will he?
但是如果你祈求一条蛇，它是魔鬼的象征，他不会给你的，是吗？
Now, if it's money you love, then you need to go to the devil worshipers to get it.
现在，如果是你爱的钱，那你就需要去找魔鬼崇拜者去拿。
Satan and his worshippers are out there in the mega churches all over the world these days
这些年代，撒旦和他的崇拜者在世界各地的大型教堂中
just waiting to appease your debauched and carnal appetites with such lies.
只是等着用这样的谎言来安抚你放荡的肉欲的欲望。
Now we come to the last line of this passage from Jesus about prayer.
现在我们来到耶稣关于祷告的这段经文的最后一行。
Remember, this is the line that most often contains the missing piece...the key to understanding all the rest.
请记住，这是最常包含缺失部分的行……这是理解所有其余部分的关键。
So listen to it carefully:
所以请仔细聆听：
"If you then, being evil, know how to give good gifts to your children
“如果你那么邪恶，还知道如何给你的孩子送好礼物
"how much more shall your heavenly Father give..."
“你们的天父会给多么好的啊……”
Give what? "How much more shall your heavenly Father give the Holy Spirit to them that ask him."
给什么？ “何况你的天父将圣灵赐给求他的人呢？”
What is the father going to give you if you keep on asking, if you keep on seeking, if you keep on knocking?
如果你继续问，如果你继续寻找，如果你继续敲门，父亲会给你什么？
What is he going to give you if you do like the widow
如果你喜欢像那个寡妇一样的求，他会给你什么
begging, pleading, and never giving up in that one overriding prayer? What will he give you?
在那个压倒一切的祷告中乞求、恳求和永不放弃,他会给你什么？
Yes! The Holy Spirit.
是的！圣灵。
Man, how have they corrupted even the whole concept of the Holy Spirit?
人啊，他们竟然连圣灵的整个概念都败坏了？
A young girl in a pentecostal orphanage said to me many years ago, "if you want the Holy Spirit
多年前，五旬节孤儿院的一个小女孩对我说：“如果你想要圣灵
"you need to get a drum."
“你需要一个鼓。”
It's so typical of how they've been trained. Beat the drum, turn up the volume, turn on the smoke machine
这是他们受训方式的典型代表。敲鼓，调大音量，打开烟机
play on the emotions, generate the tears in whatever one you can
玩弄情绪，尽你所能制造眼泪
and then tell people that they have the Holy Spirit.
然后告诉人们他们有圣灵。
That is the lie they've been feeding us for decades now,
那是他们几十年来一直在给我们灌输的谎言，
and so people tell me that because they've had an emotional dream
所以人们告诉我这是因为他们有一个情感上的梦想
or because they've survived a car crash, or because they felt goose bumps
或者因为他们在车祸中幸存下来，或者因为他们感到起鸡皮疙瘩
they now have the Holy Spirit, and all the world should listen to them.
他们现在有圣灵，全世界都应该听他们的。
Believe me, it takes a lot more than that.
相信我，这需要的远不止这些。
Having the holy spirit is a lifelong commitment.
拥有圣灵是一生的承诺。
You see churches full of spiritual perverts running from one thrill to the next
你看到教堂里到处都是属灵扭曲的人，从一种刺激跑到另一种刺激
all claiming that they have the Holy Spirit, at the same time that they resist everything that Jesus ever said.
所有人都声称他们有圣灵，同时他们抗拒耶稣所说的一切。
Those 120 disciples in the upper room waited for 10 days for the Holy Spirit to come.
楼上那120个门徒等了10天，才等到圣灵降临。
I have no doubt that they went through a lot of tears and a lot of emotional ups and downs in those 10 days
我毫不怀疑，在那10天里，他们经历了很多眼泪和很多情绪起伏
while they wrestled with God and with their own faith.
当他们与上帝和自己的信仰较力时。
I can imagine that, at each step along the way, God would ask
我可以想象，在沿途的每一步，上帝都会问
"Is that what you want? Some petty thrill? Or do you want the real thing?"
“这就是你想要的？一些小小的刺激？或者你想要真实的东西？”
I believe it was only when they reached the point when they were ready to do anything that Jesus might ask:
我相信只有当他们准备好实践耶稣教导的任何事情时：
Forsake everything they owned, quit their jobs, leave their families,
放弃他们拥有的一切，辞掉工作，离开家人，
go into all the world, lay down their lives for Christ...
到全世界去，为基督舍命……
And then the blessing came. And who knows?
然后祝福就来了。谁知道呢？
Maybe it wasn't even emotional for some of them.
也许对他们中的一些人来说，这甚至不是情绪化的。
But they had sorted it out between them and God, right down to the last breath in their bodies.
但他们已经在他们和上帝之间解决了这个问题，直到他们身体的最后一口气。
Jesus, and all that he represented, meant more to them than life itself.
耶稣，以及他所代表的一切，对他们来说比生命本身更重要。
How can we even think to mention prayer without some understanding of what it is all leading to?
我们怎么可能想到要提到祷告而不了解它会导致什么？
Your heavenly Father wants to give his Holy Spirit to them that ask.
你的天父想要将他的圣灵赐给那些祈求的人。
But there are very few who ask, and even fewer who keep on asking until they get it.
但是很少有人求，更少的人会一直求直到他们得到它。
Nevertheless, that is what the father wills. And if we are to pray according to his will
尽管如此，这是父亲的意愿。如果我们要按照他的旨意祷告
then this is what we will ask for.
那么这就是我们所要求的。
In the verses before this passage, Jesus told them to say the Lord's Prayer:
在这段经文之前的经文中，耶稣告诉他们要念主祷文：
"Your kingdom come, your will be done..."
“愿你的国降临，愿你的旨意成就……”
Where is there mention of new cars or multi-million dollar jets in that prayer?
在那个祷告中，哪里提到了新车或价值数百万美元的喷气式飞机？
Where are the promotions and healings and worldly marks of success
升职、医治和世俗的成功标志在哪里？
in what Jesus tells us to pray for, in the Lord's Prayer?
在主祷文中，耶稣告诉我们要祈求什么？
When we want his kingdom more than life itself;
当我们想要他的国过于生命本身时；
When we want his spirit more than life itself; when we want his truth and love and faith more than life itself;
当我们想要他的灵胜过生命本身时；当我们想要他的真理、爱和信仰过于生命本身时；
Then, will he open the windows of heaven and pour out his true blessing on our lives.
然后，他会打开天堂的窗户，将他真正的祝福倾倒在我们的生活中。
Can we trust him for that?
我们可以信任他吗？
Can we let him decide what it is that will really make us happy?
我们可以让他决定什么才能真正让我们快乐吗？
Believe me, he does know what is best for each of us.
相信我，他确实知道什么对我们每个人都是最好的。
So let us ask, and let us keep on asking for more and more of his spirit.
所以让我们祈求，让我们继续祈求越来越多的他的属灵。
Your will be done.
你的旨意成就。
Your kingdom come, on earth, as it is in heaven.
你的国降临在地上，在地上，如同在天上一样。
For after all is said and done, heavenly father
所有的一切，被陈述并被完成，天父
yours is the kingdom, and yours is the power, and yours is the glory, for ever and ever.
国度是你的，权势是你的，荣耀是你的，直到永远。
Can we pray such a prayer?
我们可以作这样的祷告吗？
Amen.
阿门。